Ponder this!
What walks on four legs in the morning, two
during midday, and three in the evening?
So goes the riddle of the Sphinx, the
legendary guardian of the pyramids.
The answer? Man!
Travelers who answer the riddle incorrectly
are devoured by the ravenous Sphinx.
Now, 30,000 kilometers from Japan,
Jotaro and crew have finally
reached their destination, Cairo.
Cairo is massive.
It's in our best interest to
systematically search the city,
working our way toward the center.
We're finally here.
Jotaro and the others have reached Cairo.
However,
before the team can reach Dio,
they must first navigate their way through
the many sphinxes that stand before them.
Very nice to meet you, gentlemen.
What'll you have to drink?
There's something we'd like to ask you.
My associates and I are trying
to locate this building.
Any idea where it is?
Joseph and the others
were utterly exhausted.
They had been searching
for the building in the
photograph ever since
their arrival in Cairo.
Taken with Joseph's psychic photography,
the image revealed Dio's whereabouts.
Dio had recently moved to a new hideout,
and the Speedwagon
Foundation couldn't find him.
Where was Dio hiding?
Failure to locate him as soon as possible
would spell certain doom for Holly.
I'm sorry, stranger, but this is a cafe.
You should order a drink
before asking questions.
Then iced teas, four of them.
Never seen the place.
Cairo is a city of six
million so there must
be at least two or
three million buildings.
How are we gonna find him we know he's
here there must be someone who can help us.
This is the building huh this picture
doesn't tell me anything sorry man but it
doesn't look Familiar
i see sorry to bother
you let's go we'll try somewhere else.
I happen to know where your
little building is located.
To be honest with you i'm
quite familiar with it.
This is the end
of
the game.
And the man who has been sent
to me, the king of the king
And the king of the
king has been no longer.
The place at the end of the
world is still a place to see.
Following the war, the end
of the battle of the king!
The way you die is the star of the star?
Let's go to the
end
of the world.
Ola, ola, ola, ola!
Ola,
ola,
ola!
Was that you?
Were you the one who said that?
Do you actually know
where the building is?
Yes.
The exact location of
the building in question
is information readily available to me.
Are you serious? That's incredible!
What remarkable news! Amazing!
What are the odds that
we would stumble upon
someone who knows exactly
where the building is?
Well, don't keep us in suspense.
Where's it located?
Are you really expecting
something for nothing?
Yes, you bring up a good point.
My apologies.
Ten pounds for your help?
Now then, where is it?
Hmm?
Thing is, I'm something of a gambling man.
I've been known to be a
sucker for cheap thrills,
and some would even go so
far as to say I'm an addict.
However, when all's said and done,
gambling's how I make my living.
Tell me, any of you boys like to gamble?
I'm not sure I fully understand
what you're trying to get at.
I thought I'd laid it out plainly.
If you don't like gambling, then say so.
For the last time, I have no idea
where you're going with this.
Oh, all right.
What I'm asking is if you and your
friends would like to play a little game.
Win, and I'll tell you the
location of your building.
It's as simple as that. A bet?
Look, friend, I'm as
lucky as the next guy,
but I'm afraid that we don't
have time for poker right now.
If I throw in another 20
pounds, will you tell us?
No need to worry.
A bet can be anything, after all.
It won't take very long.
For example, take a look
at that wall over there.
Do you see that cat?
So, two pieces of dried fish.
Question is, which of the
two will the cat eat first?
The right one or the left one?
I must say, there's something
thrilling about its simplicity.
Hey!
I've had just about enough of your games.
So take the money and tell us
what we want to know, you bastard!
Take it down a notch, Polnareff.
That's not the way you
ask someone for a favor.
Fine!
If it'll make you shut
up, I'll take the bet.
The cat will choose the
piece of fish on the right.
Okay.
Now it's getting interesting.
I'll be placing my bet on the left.
Polnareff.
Say, Jotaro, are you getting
a strange feeling from him?
I am.
He might be an enemy stand user.
That or he could just
be a compulsive gambler.
If he does anything at
all that seems suspicious,
you should immediately attack
him with Star Platinum.
Understood.
Let's say I lose.
It's fairly obvious that I'll
owe you a hefty amount of money.
So when a hundred pounds do...
I've no use for money.
But what would you say
to giving me your soul?
That should do just fine.
Huh? Huh?
Now the bastard thinks he's a comedian.
I wish we could get the hell out
of here and away from this freak.
Well?
Yeah, yeah, that's fine with me.
We'll do things your way.
It appears the cat has
taken notice of the fish.
Like I thought.
He's going after the one on the right.
If I were a cat, I'd pick
the bigger piece of meat.
And lucky for me, that's
the one on the right.
And there you have it.
Our feline friend took the
left, then the right, then ran.
I win this round, gentlemen.
Boy, you've outdone yourself
this time, Polnareff.
I hope you're thrilled.
How exactly are we going
to get the information
on the building's
whereabouts out of him now?
Well, if there's nothing else, as per
our agreement, it's time to pay up. Huh?
Pay? With what?
Your soul, of course.
Surely you didn't forget
about our wager pull, Nareff.
I want your soul, as I'm a stand user
who prides himself on stealing them.
I find that it's far easier to take a
person's soul if they lose it in a bet.
Which is when my stance power
activates and collects what's mine.
What the hell?
My god, what's happening?
Polnareff!
Now, now, I wouldn't be so
quick to lash out if I were you.
I know you desperately want
to kill me, but if I die,
Polnareff will meet the same end.
Polnareff! No! No!
He has no pulse!
He's dead!
Polnareff is dead!
Polnareff!
Have a look.
Polnareff's soul resides in this.
Now Lord Dio has one less meddlesome
fool to interfere with his plans.
And what a fool he was.
Please allow me to introduce myself.
My name is Darby.
Tribe.
There's an apostrophe after the D.
Gambler, Stealer of Defeated Souls,
and User of the Osiris Stand.
I believe you've had the
pleasure of meeting my cat.
What is this, you bastard?
You call that a bet?
How dare you, you vile
cheating son of a...
Cheater, you say?
Have you considered
Polnareff lost because he
lacked insight to consider
all the possibilities?
Hear me out.
Gambling is nothing more
than a simple analogy
for man's relationship with his brethren.
A dance of deception, where
the loser cries first. Yeah.
Are you planning to kill me
with your own two hands, Avdol?
Go right ahead, if you don't mind
your friend's soul being lost forever.
The choice is completely
up to you. Know this.
We're not just going to let you
waltz out of here in one piece.
Try to think back to September
Knight, 1984 at 11.15pm.
Remember what you were doing
during that time and date?
What does that even mean?
I remember it quite clearly.
I was in California,
gambling against an American that
went by the name of Stephen Moore.
He said the same thing you
just said a moment ago.
But now he's singing a more silent tune.
The chip below him is his father,
and the one next to him is his wife.
If you want Polnareff's soul back, you
have no choice but to continue our game.
How much is his life worth to you?
This man is evil incarnate.
So that's it.
He wants to capture our souls.
So what's it gonna be?
You can leave if you're
too scared to play.
I'll hold Polnareff here for safekeeping.
Why don't you fine gentlemen have a
drink and think things over a bit?
Care for a piece of chocolate?
What is this, Mr. Joestar?
What are you trying to accomplish?
I'm curious.
Do you have any idea what
surface tension is Barbie?
My name's Darby.
You know it's not Barbie.
And I assume you're
referring to how the liquor
appears to almost overflow
but stays in the glass.
So, is there a point to all this build-up?
We're playing a game.
The rules are simple.
We take turns dropping
coins into the glass.
Whoever makes the liquor
spill loses. Old man. Mr.
Joestar, you're not going to...
Exactly right!
I'm going to bet my soul!
I'm going to bet my soul! Okay.
You've got to be kidding!
You can't go through with it, Mr.
Joestar!
This man is a good-for-nothing cheater!
He won't cheat me this time.
I've decided on the rules
myself, so I'll be fine.
Jotaro, you watch for funny business.
Okay.
Since you're so determined,
I'll accept your conditions.
However, before we begin, would you
mind if I inspect the glass and coins?
Sure, have at it.
You have the right to ensure that
I'm playing on the up and up.
A question.
What guarantee do I have that you'll return
Polnareff's soul if you lose the game?
You've my word as a
gambler that I'll keep my
promise if I lose I assure
you that I will pay.
In full but I won't lose
well in that case you
can go first go ahead and
drop a coin in please.
Stop just leave everything
to me the old coin
in glass trick is one of
my specialties surface.
This tension is a
surprisingly strong force.
There's room for at least eight
or nine coins in the glass.
I just have to stay calm and
make sure my fingers don't shake.
Is it all right if I drop in more
than one coin at the same time?
As long as they all go
in at once. Well then.
What?
Five coins?
Hey, that'll create a wave on the surface.
Quiet, please.
Take your hands off the table.
It looks like it's your turn.
It takes nerves of steel to
put in five coins at once.
I think I'll go with one coin.
It's too close to call.
Typical old man.
He's squeezing a cotton
ball between his finger
and the coin to leak
liquid into the glass.
So that's how he's gonna
make the glass overflow.
And he told me to watch for cheating.
Clever bastard.
Not bad.
The glass has reached its limit!
One more coin and the booze will spill!
Victory is mine!
It's like he said, we'll see
which dance partner cries first!
Ooh, man, that was a close one!
I thought it was gonna spill for sure!
Well, it's your turn! Good luck, Obi!
It's Darby!
Don't make me say it again!
I told you my name is Darby, understand?
Not Obi, not Barbie. Hmm?
Apologies.
He's screwing up his name on purpose to
get him riled up and throw off his game.
I gotta hand it to the old man.
He's a natural.
So what do you say we keep playing?
I believe it's your turn
to drop a coin in, Darby.
The shadow makes it
difficult to see from here.
I'll lower the coin in from
the right side of the table.
Drop it in from whatever angle you'd like.
What he doesn't know is the glass is already
at its limit thanks to my little trick.
There's no way the liquid
could take another coin even.
Even the slightest touch
will cause it to spill over.
You're probably thinking the
glass has reached its limit.
That dropping in another
coin would be impossible.
Well, you'd be wrong about that.
There's no way how the
hell did he do that why
didn't it spill over
your questions confusing?
What do you mean why
didn't it spill you saw
the result with your own
eyes as far as i know?
He didn't do anything
devious i was watching
him with star platinum
it's hard to believe!
But he dropped it in fair and square.
There's no doubt.
But how did he do it?
I'm positive I added enough liquid to the
glass and one more coin
would make it spill.
I don't get it.
There's no way it shouldn't have spilled.
What's going on?
Make your move.
It's your turn, Joestar.
Hurry it up already.
Or are you trying to
wait until it evaporates?
No! No!
This can't be happening!
Oh, Mr. Jostar!
Deep in his heart of hearts,
Jostar had already come to the
realization that he'd lost this game.
That's why his soul emerged so easily.
I, Darby, have won this
bet like all the others.
Polarify, I failed you.
Ollie, I'm so sorry, my beautiful
girl, but Daddy's let you down.
Mr. Joestar! One man, no!
Two down.
Now let's continue where
we left off. That is,
unless you two have decided
to abandon your friends
and slink away with your
tails between your legs.
You bastard!
You don't get it, do you?
I keep trying to tell you that if you take
my life, your friends will die with me.
Damn you!
Antal, stand down!
Hey, if you're gonna cause trouble, then
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave...
Shut your mouth and stay out of this!
Right!
You've noticed it too late, Jotaro.
What?
Something's wrong with the glass?
This is the reason the coin
didn't make the boost spill over.
If you look at the bottom of the glass,
you'll see that there's a
tiny bit of chocolate on it.
He must have found a way to stick
it on when he was inspecting
the glass and coins at the
very beginning of the game.
Surely you know the rules by now.
It doesn't count as cheating if
you never get caught in the act.
What?
I don't understand.
How could a piece of chocolate
allow him to drop in an extra coin?
Well, at this point, it's melted,
but it used to be a solid chunk
stuck to the bottom of the glass.
Just enough to slightly tilt the glass,
but not quite enough for
us to notice the change.
Once the chocolate started to melt, the
glass came to be level with the table.
With the glass leveled out,
the booze began to settle,
which made enough room for another coin.
What the hell?
But that doesn't make any sense.
How could he have known the chocolate
would melt right when he needed it to?
He influenced things by using the sun.
It slipped my notice.
When he moved to the
right side of the table,
he allowed the sun to shine
directly onto the chocolate,
thereby melting it.
All right.
Darby, get your cards,
because we're playing my game.
Hope you're ready for some poker.
Say what?
Totoro!
Interesting.
You couldn't have possibly known this,
but poker is my absolute favorite game.
Are you out of your mind?
You're playing poker with
a man who outsmarted Mr.
Joestar!
It's too dangerous!
Yeah, I know.
Even though he doesn't
use physical strength,
he's the most dangerous
stand user we've ever faced.
So now...
There's no turning back and
we're playing for keeps.
Thank you.
Give me three cards.
Ah, I think I'll raise.
I didn't notice him do
anything suspicious.
Successful cheating requires
the element of surprise.
But there's only one Joker here.
Well then, Jotaro.
I'll bet my soul on the game's outcome.